Hankook Lee

PH.D STUDENT @ ALIN LAB IN KAIST

KAIST N1-917, 291 Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon 34141, South Korea

Research Interests

My research goal is to develop efficient and scalable deep learning algorithms that require few or no human annotation, and ultimately apply them to real-world applications with massive data. More specifically, my research interests lie in neural architectures, data augmentations, transfer/few-shot learning and un/self-supervised learning in various domains such as vision, chemistry, and tabular data.

Education

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, South Korea

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Sep. 2018 - Present

Advisor: linwoo Shin

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, South Korea

M.Sc. in Electrical Engineering

· Advisor: Jinwoo Shin

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2018

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)B.Sc. in Mathematics and Computer Science (Double major)

Daejeon, South Korea Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2016

• GPA: 3.93/4.3 (Magna Cum Laude)

Publications

C: Conference, W: Workshop, P: Preprint, *: Equal contribution

[C7/W] Improving Transferability of Representations via Augmentation-Aware Self-Supervision

Online

Hankook Lee, Kibok Lee, Kimin Lee, Honglak Lee, Jinwoo Shin

Dec. 2021

- Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021
- · International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2021 Workshop: Self-Supervised Learning for Reasoning and Perception

[C6] Self-Improved Retrosynthetic Planning

Online

Junsu Kim, Sungsoo Ahn, **Hankook Lee**, Jinwoo Shin

Jul. 2021

• International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021

[C5/W] RetCL: A Selection-based Approach for Retrosynthesis via Contrastive Learning

Online

Hankook Lee, Sungsoo Ahn, Seung-Woo Seo, You Young Song, Eunho Yang, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

Aug. 2021

- International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2021
- NeurIPS Workshop for Machine Learning for Molecules, 2020

[C4] GTA: Graph Truncated Attention for Retrosynthesis

Online

Seung-Woo Seo, You Young Song, June Yong Yang, Seohui Bae, **Hankook Lee**, Jinwoo Shin, Sung Ju Hwang, Eunho Yang

Feb. 2021

• AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021

[C3] Guiding Deep Molecular Optimization with Genetic Exploration

Online

Sungsoo Ahn, Junsu Kim, **Hankook Lee**, Jinwoo Shin

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020

Dec. 2020

[C2] Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations

Online

Hankook Lee, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

JUI. 2020

- International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020
- Received Qualcomm-KAIST Innovation Awards (2019)

[C1] Learning What and Where to Transfer

Long Beach, CA, USA

Yunhun Jang*, **Hankook Lee***, Sung Ju Hwang, Jinwoo Shin

Jul. 2019

• International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2019

[P] Anytime Neural Prediction via Slicing Networks Vertically

Hankook Lee, Jinwoo Shin Jul. 2018

arXiv preprint

Work Experience _____

SAIT (Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology)

Visiting student

Suwon, South Korea Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

• Developed ML-based retrosynthesis algorithms (AAAI 2021, IJCAI 2021 papers).

Frograms Seoul, South Korea

Research and Development Engineer

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

- · Built an automatic movie tagging system using movies' news/reviews based on Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA).
- Built a Scala-based movie rating prediction system based on non-negative matrix factorization.
- The incorporation name was changed to Watcha Inc. at 2018.

Honors & Awards

20	19 Winner , Qualcomm-KAIST Innovation Awards (ICML 2020 paper)	Daejeon, South Korea
20	19 Travel award, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2019	Long Beach, CA, USA
20	13 Finalist , International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) World Finals	St. Petersburg, Russia
20	12 1st Place (Grand Prize), International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) Asia Daejeon Regional	Daejeon, South Korea
20	2nd Place (Gold Prize), International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) Asia Daejeon Regional	Daejeon, South Korea
20	09 Gold Prize , Problem Solving Division, Korea Olympiad in Informatics (KOI)	Seoul, South Korea

Services_

2022 Conference Reviewer, ICLR 2022

2021 Conference Reviewer, ICLR 2021, ICML 2021, NeurIPS 2021

2020 Conference Reviewer, ICLR 2020, NeruIPS 2020

Journal Reviewer, ACM ToMPECS 2020 2020

Journal Reviewer, ACM ToMPECS 2018 2018

Invited Talks_

2021	Self-supervised Label Augmentation via Input Transformations, Samsung Electronics DIT Center	Hwaseong, South Korea
2020	Learning What and Where to Transfer, Samsung Electronics DIT Center	Hwaseong, South Korea
2019	Learning What and Where to Transfer, Summer Annual Conference of IEIE	Jeju, South Korea
2018	Anytime Neural Prediction via Slicing Networks Vertically, NAVER Labs	Seongnam, South Korea

Teaching Experience

2020	TA: "Semantic Segmentation and Object Detection", Samsung DS AI Expert Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Yongin, South Korea
2019	TA: "Optimization and Regulaization", SK Hynix ML Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Daejeon, South Korea
2019	TA: "Transfer and Multi-task Learning", Samsung DS AI Expert Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Daejeon, South Korea
2018	TA , Seongnam-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Seongnam, South Korea
2018	TA, KB-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Daejeon, South Korea
2017	TA, KB-KAIST AI Program (Instructor: Jinwoo Shin)	Seoul, South Korea

HANKOOK LEE · CURRICULUM VITAE OCTOBER 7, 2021